THOMAS MUAT

58 Fareham Avenue, Rugby, Warwickshire, CV22 5HT Thomas_Muat@hotmail.com +447738210256

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I have recently left the sports performance analysis industry; having spent the last seven years working in applied analysis within professional rugby environments. Within my role I worked alongside the first team staff to utilise video and large datasets to inform decision making for our performance. I am a highly motivated and enthusiastic individual with a BA (Hons) in Sports Coaching and Physical Education.

EMPLOYMENT



Wasps

1st XV Lead Performance Analyst

July 2018-July 2020

- •Lead the day to day management of all performance analysis activities.
- •Lead the opposition SWOT analysis in collaboration with the other performance analysts.
- Lead on all post-match reporting including both team and individual.
- •Work with the Head of Performance Analysis on yearly budgets.
- •Work to ensure the performance analysis department stays at the forefront of techniques and technology to assist in the provision provided to the XV players and staff.
- •Working in collaboration with the performance analysis team, to formulate longitudinal reports on performance.
- •Ensure safe and effective use of drones used to film training sessions.
- •Worked to ensure all performance data was stored in secure and efficient environments for any analysis needing to be undertaken.
- •Along with the responsibilities listed below as 1st XV Performance Analyst.



Wasps

1st XV Performance Analyst

July 2015-June 2018

- •Provide performance analysis support to elite level athletes and coaches, working collaboratively as part of a wider multi-disciplinary support staff aimed at enhancing performance.
- •Produce weekly opposition SWOT analysis, utilising both statistical and video evidence for the coaching team.
- •Produce, maintain and update weekly databases of opposition footage as well as longitudinal performance data, allowing for trends in performance to be extracted from large datasets.
- •Collaborate with coaches to prepare and deliver weekly team and unit preview meetings in a time pressured environment.
- •Responsible for care and handling of analysis hardware.
- •Provide capture and coding of training on a daily basis.
- Provide team coding for statistical output and review during matches for the Wasps coaching team.
- •Managing the club's online portal, allowing players and coaches to view material when away from the club.
- •Completing additional day to day requirements of the analysis department.



1st XV Lead Performance Analyst

August 2013-May 2015

- •Lead the pre to post match analysis process for the London Scottish 1st XV.
- •Filming & coding of training sessions.
- •Collaborate with coaches to prepare and deliver weekly team and unit preview meetings.
- •Provided live statistical outputs for the coaching team.
- •Produced team & player match reports for distribution to coaches & players.
- •Developed & maintained a recruitment database for use by all staff involved in the recruitment process.

Additional Relevant Experience/Qualifications

 Academy Performance Analyst Intern at Reading Football Club (Volunteer) (October 2012-January 2013)

EDUCATION

University of Chichester

BA Sports Coaching & Physical Eduction

2:1

September 2010-2014

SKILLS

- •A basic knowledge of Python & R.
- •An ability to create workflows using multiple programs such as SportsCode, Microsoft Office and Apple iWorks to extract information and present reports from large datasets.
- •Experience working in time pressured environments.
- •A comprehensive knowledge and experience in using Microsoft Excel to manage large data sets and extract the most pertinent information through advanced formula and VBA.
- •Experience in using programs such as Final Cut, ScreenFlow, Elgato Turbo, Handbrake, and IBM SPSS.
- •Comfortable working within a multi-disciplinary team.
- •An understanding of forming relationships and working with external contractors and companies.
- •An efficient communicator and good at forming relationships with co-workers.